SUNNY OGBARI

+2348170143886 | sunny.ogbari@gmail.com | Lagos, Nigeria | www.linkedin.com/in/sunnyogbari | Github | Portfolio

PROFILE SUMMARY

Frontend Developer with over two years of experience creating software solutions for clients in industries including health tech and finance. Extensive experience in all phases of software development, including implementing multiple projects involving cross-functional teams that directly impacted the business processes of various companies.

CORE COMPETENCIES

•	Software Development	•	Database Management	•	Process Optimization
•	Workflow Automation	•	Solutions Deployment	•	Stakeholder Engagement
•	Codebase Management	•	Software Testing	•	Object Oriented Design
•	Debugging	•	Project Management	•	Technical Documentation

SKILLSET AND COMPETENCIES

•	Programming Languages: TypeScript, HTML, CSS,	•	Business Automation: ProcessMaker
	SASS, SCSS	•	Project Management: Jira
•	Frameworks: React.js, NextJS	•	Others: Figma

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer - FSDH Merchant Bank | Lagos, Nigeria

Management Libraries: React, Redux, Bootstrap

Apr. 2022 - Present

- Eliminated redundancies in business operations by 12% by automating 30% of the bank's existing processes and designing and implementing new processes in collaboration with product managers, and backend and frontend developers.
- Built web applications and portals for internal use that directly translated into better company-wide performance by reviewing business requirements documents and developing designs according to business specifications.
- Designed and built an API dashboard that improved the transactions overview for hundreds of clients while documenting 3 external APIs; FSDH 360, FSDH Pay, and FSDH BVN API.
- Leveraged responsive web frameworks to consistently complete in-house project deliverables of converting Figma and XD designs into HTML, CSS, and JSX ahead of schedule.
- Improved outcomes for end users by deploying REST APIs to enhance seamless information exchange with third parties.
- Executed and contributed to full-stack web development projects, focusing on frontend features, browser manipulation, and cross-browser compatibility.
- Completed the following projects that involved designing with Figma and working with backend developers to implement;
 - Nigerian Export Supervision Scheme Fee (NESS)
 - Letters of Credit (LC portal)
 - Telex Email Interface
 - Customer Risk Rating platform

Tab Tech Software Solutions

Frontend Developer

Jun. 2020 - Apr. 2022

- Identified new needs and requirements and participated in designing products with multiple developers to implement different solutions for organizations.
- Optimized the product order management for 1med Solutions through frontend redesign and API integration for the admin dashboard.
- Designed the Seven Up Bottling Company collections branch assist interface and the Prestige Portal.
- Automated the task tracker for other employees using React JS and managed frontend designs that provided solutions to internal efficiency.
- Converted 247electric from Figma to HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and developed the 247electric admin interface using React JS, HTML, and CSS.
- Worked with the Solutions Architect in mentoring other Junior Developers in Frontend Development.

Software Tester Jun. 2020 - Apr. 2022

• Analyzed the business requirement for mobile and web applications, created test strategies, and generated the test planes.

- Worked with a team of product managers, software testers, and backend and frontend developers to test manually.
- Performed manual testing and API testing, and regression testing on mobile and web applications.
- Executed test cases to test application functionality against the requirement manually.
- Interacted with developers and users to communicate defects actively while understanding software requirements and specifications and identifying test scenarios.
- Reported bugs using Jira and utilized resources to meet mobile and web application specifications by analyzing expected input/output results.

EDUCATION

•	Bachelors of Arts in English Education – University of Lagos, Nigeria	Sept. 2015
PR	OFESSIONAL AFFILIATION AND CERTIFICATE	
•	Soft-Skills Training – Jobberman Nigeria	2021
•	Web Design and Development - Side Hustle NG	2021